And and actually that's a really
interesting point. You know, I think
after you get in the live hacking event
scene and you've seen like show and
tells of other people's bugs and you've
like went and talked to them a little
bit, you kind of have like a a rolodex
for lack of a better word of like, oh,
this bug, this person.
>> Best part of when you can just, you
know, critical thinking, right?
[music]
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, dude.
>> Sup, Packers? We've got an exciting
announcement. Threat Locker Zero Trust
World Conference is back in 2026. It's
going to be March 4th to March 6 in
Orlando, Florida. It's freaking gorgeous
down there, too, during that time. And
yours truly is going to be there. I'm
going to be there on Wednesday, March
4th. I'm going to be leading a hands-on
hacking workshop. I'll be one of many.
So, there's lots of fun hacking
workshops you can get involved in. Um,
and it's going to be a great time.
There's tons of sessions, workshops,
other people there to network with. It's
going to be a great conference. So, if
you're local to Orlando or if you're up
for the travel, um, this is a great way
for you to use that employer uh,
training budget that you've got. Also,
um, for critical thinking listeners,
there's a discount of $200 off. You can
use the code ZTW, right, for zero trust
world. CTB26.
ZTWCTBB26
when you register. That'll be on the
screen and in the description as well.
It's going to be a great time. I hope to
see you guys there. All right, let's go
back to the show.
Yo, dude, that was a crazy hackalong we
had in the Discord yesterday.
>> Yeah, it was. Yeah, I think you know,
obviously we we talked about me doing
hackalongs last year and uh we didn't
actually do any. So, but it is nice. We
have a master class coming up. I'm
teaching a master class on FFUF this
this month. But uh dude, my brain felt
like absolute spaghetti while I was
doing it.
>> It's so hard.
>> Really hard. I think that I definitely
would have put way more time into prep
had I thought that
>> had it felt more like normal hacking.
Like I definitely It didn't feel like
normal hacking at all. It felt like I
was just like totally scatterrained.
Like because it's like you can't keep a
single train of thought on what you're
hacking on because you're switching to
well one you're trying to think like oh
I need to talk then you're trying to
switch and rehat and then you also have
other people talking to you like in the
form of which is actually helpful right
having the other kind of co-host at the
time talking to you to bounce ideas off
of but man too many info streams to my
brain.
>> Yeah. So, so for any of you guys that
didn't catch it in the Discord, we did a
charity hackalong, a uh a 10-hour long
marathon hackalong in the CTPB Discord.
[snorts] Um, and the way that we had it
structured is we had five people doing
two hours each. Um, and we we tried to
have at least one other like sort of
co-host there while the person's hacking
because when for for any of you guys
that have not actually like tried to
live narrate your hacking while you're
hacking, it is so hard. It is
>> much harder than expected.
>> Extremely hard. Um, so shout out to uh
Mon and XSS Doctor um and Bus for for
jumping in there along with me and Reszo
to do that. And uh yeah, I mean the
hackalong team, XSS doctor and bus
factor
>> and I, you know, we've had our reps
>> on this, so we we know what to expect
going into it, but uh you and Mona were
cutting your teeth on this, I think.
>> Oh my goodness, it was rough. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I mean, you have to learn you have
to learn at some point. Uh but yeah,
your all sections were very clean in
regards to
>> it being like clearly good technical
output and staying on topic with one
thing and achieving one goal and so
Yeah.
>> Yeah. Well, the h the handoff between
Doc and I was great because, you know,
he did he did a lot of he did a lot of
prep work in his first two hours, you
know, found this amazing scope, got
things set up, figured out a threat
model, and then, you know, sussed most
of the exploit. And I just kind of got
there, you know, and was able to close
it out in the in the last like, you
know, in my two hours. And then we got
those uh we got two reports in from that
from those two. Um, and then we kept
plugging along and I think we'll get one
more. We're like very close to getting
our third like full um exploit uh
submitted uh for the for the charity
hackalong. So it was exciting man. I do
have some technical takeaways. Did you
have any that you wanted to bring up or
should I just jump right into mine?
>> Uh yeah, go ahead jump into yours. But I
do have some uh things to bring up about
it. Yeah.
>> Okay. So um you know first thing up here
was uh when you are doing so one of the
bugs that we found you know without
going into too much detail was a post
messagebased race condition. Okay so
what was happening is um there was an
iframe being loaded on the page and the
top level um you know page would then
send a sort of initialization message
down to the the iframe. Okay. And uh
what we could do in that environment was
we could race condition it from a third
party page right from an attacker
controlled page and um and send our you
know our post message and then hijack
control of the iframe. Um
the problem is is when you do
window.open open a lot of times it will
like throttle your your JS um execution
environment and you just won't be able
to like either you won't be able to send
the messages from your attacker control
page because it's not the one that's
being displayed. Yeah, dude. We both got
the critical drinking mug. Let's go. Um
or you will not be able to receive
messages as quickly because that page is
in the background, right? Yeah. So it
it's a little bit of a problem and we we
fought with it for a little while and
the solution that we came up with for
this actually is do window.open with a
width and height parameter which will
create like a a pop-up window you know
that has that window open and also the
tab behind it open right and then both
windows are sort of visible to the user
so Chrome is like I need to make sure
that both of them have like a fully
functional JS execution environment.
Yeah. And then the the post messages go
burr and like you know you see 10,000
you know post messages sent immediately.
And
>> so is that like was that like a new
tactic that you had before?
>> I I hadn't seen it before. I'm sure
somebody's done it, you know, but like
that was just us kind of ideulating in
the moment, you know, and observing that
our execution environment was getting
throttled. Um so that was a fun takeaway
for me.
>> Yeah. Actually, so as you were talking I
was like, "Oh man, there are lots of
good takeaways." like basically things
that I thought were exciting or
interesting while we were hacking are
things that our our audience would think
are really exciting. So on the on this
target there was this um kind of um neat
way that you could get half off and I
don't know if you were paying attention
during that time so I'll go ahead and
tell you about it and you might think
it's really interesting.
>> Yeah. So if you tried to log in let's
say we were hacking on example.com
[snorts]
>> if you but it's a SAS platform. If you
try to log in with an email address that
is like reszo@acample.com,
it would take you to to their octa page
instead of the traditional login flow.
>> Okay.
>> Now, when now when you navigate back to
example.com and click login again,
if you log in with any other email, you
now in a different state because you got
some sort of partial cookies from that
first going to octa.
And what that allowed us to do was we
could create we could we could log in
under any email. So I was logged into
the SAS app as reszo@google.com
as like a in some sort of partial off
state, right?
>> And we didn't end up finding a bug with
this. I almost guarantee there's bugs
here because it feels so wrong and so
weird.
>> I'm sure.
>> But um but I thought it'd be good for
the listener to think just like how I
threat modeled it. So my mind
immediately went to what works and what
doesn't here and are there any places
where there are like recommended
teammates or recommended you know
documents or recommended things you can
join in case there's any kind of
protection that are domain based. Now
all of a sudden you're kind of like past
that and this this SAS company we were
hacking on has a parent SAS company that
they were acquired by. And so if you
actually went to manage your profile, it
would take you to that parent SAS
website still logged in as that partial
off as atgoogle.com.
>> You would think this fascinating. We
should actually look at this later
because I think you would think it's
really interesting.
>> So but what we did and I think this is
like a good takeaway for the listener is
one do weird stuff like that. If you can
ever get into a partial off state, it's
obviously very valuable. But then it's
like what do you do next? So what what I
did next which I think was the right
move was basically pull all of the API
endpoints and all of the even like
single page app endpoints and then
basically try to nav to them or fuzz
them with that partial off like with the
cookies and the bear tokens that we had
to see like
>> because let's say you know example.com
or like let's say at google.com let's
say that I could pull other members from
at Google or other documents from at
Google rap because I have o where I
actually have like a signed cookie or a
signed token
that is um signed with an at Google, you
know, email address in there. And so
that may let give her me some sort of
access to at Google data inside of the
SAS platform. And so anyways, we I went
down that route um and I thought it was
really interesting and yeah, we should
look at it later,
>> dude. Totally. And and whenever you say
this bug, like three three hackers come
to my mind. Okay, you've got OXACV,
right? He's always he's done a ton of
stuff with this sort of exploit. You've
got uh Cash Money
>> and Enosion, right? These guys are like
the the you know crazy dudes who know
how to exploit.
>> Yeah. So, you know, and and actually
that's a really interesting point. You
know, I think after you get in the live
hacking event scene and you've seen like
show and tells of other people's bugs
and you've like went and talked to them
a little bit, you kind of have like a a
rolodex for lack of a better word of
like, oh, this bug, this person, you
know, and uh and so that's definitely
some sketchy environment and
functionality you got And I've seen
people manipulate that so many times,
especially like you said in shared O
environments, right, where you are able
to like take your partial O from this
app and then like single sign on into
some other app where they just sign a
JBT and ye it over to the other the
other app, right? And then they have a
lot less context.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Like Kieran was convinced
that it wouldn't really work like to
like do like login with other places
with SSO because we didn't have like
true SSO. But that parent SAS company,
they own lots of little companies or
lots of little products. when I went to
every one of them, I had partial off on
all of them. So, there was some sort of
parent off there. And then the um
>> yeah, I don't know what I was going to
say, but
>> it's it's it's it's tricky, man. It it's
it's a fun bug to exploit and uh
definitely a good attack vector. And
that that was one of the things that was
really cool about the hackalong, too, is
like Doc did a bunch of prep, you know,
uh beforehand to find us really
interesting scope, which I really
appreciated, you know, like he came in
like, "Hey, look, I I started looking at
this company. This is the scope we need
to look at." And boy was he right, you
know, and because of that, you know, we
were able to pop two bugs in like 3
hours, you know. Um, which was really
cool. Uh, so shout out to Doc and and
and Bus for putting it together like the
the our our hackalong team is amazing
and uh and yeah, it just like you said
the being able to narrate while you're
hacking is such a unique skill and those
guys are really really cranking out some
reps in that.
>> Yeah. And Eugi too for helping us
organize all of it.
>> Yeah. So it was Bus's idea. He usually
helped orchestrate things and we got it
pulled off. But
>> dude, I would like to bring side note,
but I I would like to bring the whole
team on the pod at some point. I feel
like the pod needs to meet like Richard
and Eugi and
>> Yes, that'd be a really good the whole
squad.
>> If we think it'd be too much right at
once, we could just like do segments,
right? It's like do a Eugi segment, do a
Richard segment. That'd be really cool.
>> Yeah, we could. We could. Or we could
like do a maybe we'll do like a behind
the scenes episode of the pod for uh for
the uh the critical thinkers on
>> talk about how we're doing prep and all
the things. That'd be good.
>> Yeah, that'd be fun. Um all right, so
back to the takeaways. Um the the other
takeaway is an interesting uh code
pattern that I saw here. Um and this is
the one that allowed this is one of the
code patterns that allowed us to do the
race condition exploit. Um there's this
uh code pattern that I saw in the JS
where it says okay if the message is
coming from um a uh certain window
reference then allow it through
>> or if they have the secret right so and
and then the the flow would be the the
secret would always come from the that
allowed frame reference right and then
it would set the secret and then anybody
who had the secret could talk to it
Um, the thing is, uh, because you've got
an or statement there, if even if you're
sending from another frame reference,
right, it's going to fail that first
condition, it's going to go to the
second condition and see if you have the
secret. Well, if the the top level frame
hasn't set the secret yet, the secret
defaults to undefined. So, if you just
don't provide a secret, then it just
lets you write through, [snorts]
>> right?
>> So, uh, yeah, I just think that's a
really interesting pattern. Anytime you
see a secret being set, you know, as a
part of the flow, you've got to think
about how are they doing off before that
secret set.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. And and you know, maybe there's a
a precondition, right? You know, the
frame reference thing, but if they're
also checking the secret, you know, then
what is that secret initialized to? Um
is a really good good pattern and a way
to get off bypass. Um
>> dude, this would be a little bit meta
and I don't know, there's like a very
small subset of people that would really
enjoy it. I would love to watch it
though. I think it'd be interesting to
see you watch back your hackalong just
like certain segments like when you were
scrolling through JS code and and walk
the walk the audience through what's
going through your mind cuz there were
like two or three times whenever you
were just like you know in Chrome
DevTools and you were looking at the at
the JavaScript and you were like, "Oh, I
want to look at that. Oh, I want to look
at that later." And it's like you didn't
tell why. And that's fine, right? I
mean, it's it's impossible to articulate
everything. But in both those moments, I
was like cuz that happened over the span
of like 10 seconds. You said that two or
three times. And I was like, what about
this JavaScript is interesting to him.
Like I know he's not able to fully gro
everything this JavaScript is doing in
that 3 seconds. Like, you know, you can
kind of follow along, but there was
clearly indicators there of things that
were very interesting to you that almost
made your like eyes go wide. And I don't
think it was like sources or syncs. It
wasn't typical stuff that most people
like key in on. And so I was really
curious what was going through your head
at that moment. And so it' be
interesting if you did because there's
so many um YouTube videos where people
do like watch alongs or whatever. Yeah,
it's kind of like, you know, with those
video game people, right, where they'll
do like like VOD VOD reviews or
something, you'll have like a like
professional player watch the the VOD
from like the the, you know,
>> and they'll say, "At this point, he's
looking right here because when that
popped up, he knew he needed to skip
those three steps or whatever."
>> Huh. VOD reviews for hacking. That's an
interesting concept. Maybe we'll we'll
toy around with that in the uh in the
Discord.
>> Huh, that's fun. I like that
>> because like it's hard for you to
articulate everything that's going
through your head when you're doing it.
But in retrospect when you can go as
slow as you want you can say like oh
yeah right here this was the key piece
of information that made me think this
was vulnerable or what have you.
>> Yeah. or if you know maybe even someone
from the community was like hey here's a
VOD of me trying to do a hackalong
essentially right narrating my own
methodology and I can say okay well you
know here you're you're burning time
going down this route but you really
should have just validated the attack
vector first by doing this you know and
then you would have seen that that
wasn't going to work and then you would
skip it you know and then you would have
saved all that time right um so that's a
I mean especially with client side stuff
that's doable with server side stuff
it's like okay you're just churning
through attack vectors you know most of
the I was okay. I'm so glad you said
that. That was my next point. So, this
is really interesting. I felt like that
was bad hacking. Maybe not bad hacking,
but less interesting hacking. But it's
kind of what you all do with front end,
too. But I I felt I felt self-conscious
about it like like just like let's say,
you know, I'm doing a hackalong and I
I'm like looking at a request and replay
and I'm just like modify a parameter,
send it. Modify a parameter, send it. Go
down, change the body, send it. Right?
And like some of those things I could
automate with shift if they're like very
wrote. And some of those things you
could send to automate if it's like oh
just try a whole bunch of special
characters in this one spot. But a lot
of times it's not that. It's like let me
change this field. Let me add a field.
Let me change the path. You know let me
manipulate this header or whatever. And
I think um so do you think that there
are different styles that are more
conducive to hackalongs or like live
hacking or do you think I just need to
like get over that and that's actually
interesting enough for the audience and
it should be done?
>> Yeah. Well, certainly I think there's
both, but I think there's tiers to it as
well. Like for example, Matt Brown stuff
on YouTube with hardware hacking, like
he's got such a great niche for that
because you can take it the whole the
whole way, right? The problem with our
hackalongs is like we had to do multiple
times yesterday, you get to a point
where it's too close to a actual live
vulnerability and you've got to cut the
stream for a couple minutes and submit
the report,
>> right? you know and and whereas with you
know with Matt Brown stuff you can do uh
you know hardware hackalongs on a device
that you you know you own that's your
property
>> and and you can show how it's done you
know um so there's that and then I think
you know client side stuff is a little
bit in the middle c certainly server
side stuff is a lot of like all right
try that attack vector try that attack
vector and churning through that is
really good for the listeners I think to
see um but client side stuff is a little
bit more like I need this primitive I
need this primitive here's the code,
right? Here's why this isn't going to
work. Here's why this could work, you
know? So, I think you're able to justify
your your uh you know, hacker intuition
or your methodology a little bit more on
client side because you have the source
code
>> because it's a little more open source.
Yeah. Basically, open source is or I
guess white box hacking is a little bit
more interesting because there's more
aspects to it instead of just like fire
and forget, fire and forget, fire and
forget.
>> Exactly. Exactly. Yeah, that's kind of
what I think about it. Um, all right.
La, last one here was, uh, I wanted to
shout this out. Um, one of the thing
areas that I think my eyes were open to
during a Google live hacking event is
vulnerabilities in the um, permission
settings that a browser has uh, for um,
peripherals. So, your camera, your
microphone, etc. Um sometimes on on many
websites we delegate, you know, those
permissions to the website always. We're
just like, you know what, fine. Um you
know, we're on Riverside. Riverside, you
can always access my camera, right? Like
in my microphone. Like you don't need to
ask every single time, right? Um the
problem with that is when these sites
then further delegate those permissions
down to an attacker controlled iframe.
>> Um and I I saw this in in a Google live
hacking event. Really really interesting
stuff. And we were able to exploit this
in the hackalong as well where um you're
able to craft an iframe such that the
allow um HTML attribute on the iframe is
uh is set to microphone and camera and
then if that iframe is embedded in a
page that has that that access the
microphone and camera or uh microphone
and camera access you know perpetually
then that access will be delegated down
to the attacker control dira. So
essentially what what you can do is u
you can just redirect the user to a page
where you know your attacker controlled
iframe exists hijack those permissions
and you know take a picture or record uh
from the microphone.
>> Do you think that in an ideal like
Chrome architecture that that wouldn't
be allowed that iframe shouldn't be able
to inherit it that it would actually
reprompt the user like hey this iframe
is trying to load those permissions do
you actually want to approve or deny
again? I do. I do. I don't think
>> that feels right to me.
>> Well, we're gonna have to bleep that. Uh
Richard bleeped that. I don't think any
any um target uh should be able to
delegate your camera and microphone
permissions to a third party without
your permission. Right. That seem
>> Yes. I mean, I don't think they're going
to fix that anytime soon. So, go use
this on all your bug bounty targets. But
in general, I think that's the right
design.
>> Yeah. It's legacy now. You know, they
they can't they can't fix it
unfortunately. you know, the backwards
compatibility is going to break it, but
um yeah, it's a little bit unfortunate
for sure.
>> Is this something you can actually g for
through JavaScript files?
>> Um, could we create like a scanner for
this almost? It seems like it could be.
>> Yeah, I mean, just kind of using your
understanding of the business logic also
would work where you can say, okay, you
know, this website does get access to my
uh camera and my microphone, right? Um,
so,
>> you know, does it does it?
>> Maybe I should look for there. Yeah,
exactly. and and do those iframes have
the allow attribute because you know the
thing is is like that allow attribute is
pretty rare. Um but sometimes they just
like throw it on there uh and I don't
think they understand you know what the
implications of that are. Um and you
know maybe they'll come back and say hey
that's intended but
you know the PSC I built was pretty
convincing right where it's like
>> yeah and that just doesn't make any
sense if you're in like an ecosystem
where it's userbuilt apps.
>> Yeah. Exactly. Yeah. So
>> even if even if it's only company
accounts, it's like not every company
can be trusted, right?
>> Yeah. Exactly. Exactly. Um okay, so
that's a wrap on the um you know
hackalong recap. Did you did you have
anything else from the hackalong?
>> Um no, the one thing I was going to say
was Man, I thought the thing that I
missed the that I forgot earlier, I
re-remembered, but I've already
forgotten that again. So [laughter]
we'll move on,
>> dude.
Yesterday was a complete blur, which we
did have like a kids appointment in the
morning that was like a lot of
information and all the things. But
yeah, I mean after the hackalong last
night, we actually had like Bible study
last night. I couldn't think. I kept
doing this exact same thing where I
started to think of things and they
would just evaporate out of my head. And
I'm blaming the hackalong for all of it.
>> That's so validating, dude. That is so
validating to hear cuz I like left that
yesterday and I and but you know, and
then there were a lot of us there were
that were there for like four or six
hours or whatever.
>> Um but like Doesn't help that I was
listening in way for a long time before
I joined. Right.
>> Exactly. And then and then you you know
you leave and you're like, "Okay, now I
just got to like essentially I realized,
hey, my brain is going to be fried, so
I'm just going to go work on a bunch of
like admin tasks, you know, and and just
did a bunch of like boring [__] for the
rest of the day."
>> Um, okay. So, if you want to catch that
uh charity hackalong, that's in the
Critical Thinkers Discord. Um,
ctbb.show/isord.
You can join and get access to that
recording. It should be up by the time
this episode airs.
>> Some of it scuff some of it's scuffed.
Warning, but Justin's section is not. So
that's the most important part.
>> Yes. Yes, that's true. Um, all right.
Let's jump into some of the other
content. Um, I did want to cover, um,
let's share this window. Yeah, that
works. Um, so I came across, uh, you
know, an old writeup, uh, by insert
script, who is an excellent client side
hacker. Um, and it taught me something
about post messages. Uh, which is always
something interesting to me. Um, I did
not know that you can get e.source, you
know, on on a post message event to
equal null. Um, I know that you could
get the origin to equal null, uh, by
putting it in a sandboxed iframe. Uh,
but I did not know you could get e dots
source to to equal null. So, um, the way
that you do this, uh, oh, and also I
just I'll give credit where credit is
due here. This technique was um
discovered by uh security MB uh who I
believe is a Googler um and
>> six years ago.
>> That's
>> Yeah. No, it was it was a long time ago.
Yeah. Um but it it's still relevant. Um
and the the way you do that is you do an
iframe, you know, with no source and
then you do frames or frame zero eval
and you run your your code, right? And
then immediately after that you do inner
html of that frame to something else.
And what that will do somehow is that
post message that gets sent will have
event source null. Um which is really
helpful for scenarios where and this
ties back into the hackalong where
you've got you know it's being compared
to something that is uninitialized
because null is equal equal to undefined
>> undefined. Yeah.
>> In in the JavaScript world. So if you're
seeing a loose comparison um uh then you
can utilize this to to bypass um event
source checks which is one of the most
robust checks in the post message world.
>> Um so very cool technique here from uh
security MV.
>> Yeah, that's awesome. How did you find
that?
>> Uh he I think somebody I think insert
script tweeted out a like PC of it. Uh
he's like yeah just you know I wrote
wrote this up but I hadn't done a PC so
here's the PC. Um, and I and and so I
kind of went back to that and saw it and
I thought that was pretty cool to shout
out on the pod. Um,
>> these little gems, these little nuggets
are what I want my um, like AI assistant
to basically be able to reference when
I'm asking questions about like tough
stuff like this, you know.
>> Yeah. Well, I I think, you know, I think
what Bus is doing with like Bug Bounty
today,
>> um, if we can just go back and get like
a mass reference of every single like
Bug Bounty related blog or something
like that, I mean, that's just going to
be such a valuable source for AI to just
slurp it up, you know?
>> Um, [snorts]
did you like my sound effect there with
that?
>> I did like that.
>> Slip it up. [laughter]
>> Um, okay. Uh, oh, I did have something
else here. Um, I realized also that I
not only am I using fuff like a caveman.
Thank you, uh, you know, social media
team that made that the headline of a
YouTube video that went like did
numbers. Um, but also, uh, I realized
that I am hijacking the body of frames
like a caveman. Uh, because if it's same
origin, you can just do what he does
right here. You can just do frames.
Eval,
>> right? And in the past, well, what I
would do is like, for example, the open
face iframe sandwich um scenario where
you've got, [snorts] you know, an
attacker controlled page with an iframe
third party with XSS and then you've got
a victim page with an iframed third
party, right? And then you reach over
with your XSS into that, you know,
victim page and control that iframe. The
way I was doing that was just reaching
over and then doing something like
writing an SVG with an onload handler
into that DOM. But really, you know,
because it's same origin, you can just
reach over to the frame reference and do
>> eval. Eval. Yeah.
>> Yeah. And it will just run the code over
there. Um, so I I realized that the
other day and then I saw him using this
technique here and it reminded me to
shout that out on the pod just in case
anybody else was doing it the dumb way
like I was.
>> There are probably so many things where
people are just using tools suboptimally
and stuff like that. I think that this
is one huge use case for things like
CTB. It's just like
>> you would never [snorts] know if you
didn't hear someone else say, you know,
say how they do it.
>> Totally. Totally. Um, and so on the same
vein, we've also have uh he tweeted out
another PC insert scripted. Um, and this
one uh is really useful in CSPT
environment, which of course, you know,
I love I love CSPTs. Um, one of the
controls that the browsers have been
putting in place is that if you redirect
uh off of a CSPT, sometimes it'll drop
the authorization header if you're going
to a different host, right? Which is
super annoying because you're like, you
know, you get the CSPT, you hit you
finally find a redirect, you hit your
host, and you're hoping for just an easy
atto by snagging that authorization
header. Um uh however um here we can see
right here um this page showcases that
the authorization header is dropped by
modern browsers and redirects but other
custom headers like XC surf token or
not. This behavior is relevant for
client side path traversals where the
subsequent API request uses the
authorization header or other custom
headers and the API suffers from an open
redirect. The rule is if the original
request is not targeting a same origin
endpoint include the authorization
header in case of a redirect. if the
original request is targeting the same
origin endpoint, drop the authorization
header in case of a redirect. So, and
origin is strict, right? So, if you're
on, you know, www.site.com, you've got a
CSPT to api.site.com,
>> right? If you hit a redirect, it the
authorization header will be included
because that's not same origin,
>> right? Um, it's a little tricky because,
you know, redirects are less common on
APIs than they are on main domains.
Yeah. But um useful nonetheless to know
that you're not always just screwed with
if it's in the authorization header. If
it's if it's you know hitting a origin
where um you know that it's not same as
the originating origin then uh you will
actually be able to get the
authorization header through the
redirect.
>> So you do want your redirect to live on
the domain that you're trying to pass.
>> You don't want it to.
>> Oh, you don't. So, so in this case, in
your example, you just said you want the
redirect on API dot or you want the
redirect on dubdubdub.
>> You want it on API dot. Got
>> because that's not same origin as
dubdubdub,
>> right?
>> Does that make sense?
>> Why would it drop it on same origin?
That feels like kind of weird. You would
think, I don't know, just like
intuitively
>> because, you know, if it's www, right,
and then it's sending to www, it's like,
oh, it's sending to itself. Oh, it's
redirecting to a third party now. That's
weird. Let's drop it, right? But if it's
if it's a third, you know, and it's not
same site, which is interesting. I would
assume it would be same site, but it's
not same origin.
>> Yeah.
>> Um so, uh yeah, just good to keep in
mind that even if it's same site in
different origin, you're still going to
get that follow on the redirect.
>> Um
>> really great research.
>> So this is so this is also a reason why
you wouldn't want to roll your own off.
Like you want to use the authorization
header if you're a de a developer
because the browser is building in a
little bit of protection for you in
certain use cases. Whereas if you did X
dash authorization, you would not get
that protection.
>> Correct. Yeah. So architecturally that's
a safer a safer decision and you can
still leak things like X curve token or
whatever, but um you know definitely not
as impactful as just dropping your off
token, you know,
>> right? Yeah, for sure.
>> Yeah.
>> Um all right. Did you have one you
wanted to hop to?
>> Um yeah, sweet. Um I'm trying to think.
Okay, cool. Yeah, I'll do a nonAI one
first. Um.
>> Mhm.
>> Joel and I I don't think you know about
this yet. Do you know about this?
>> No.
>> Joel and I. So, yeah. Uh, you know, the
previous co-host, uh, Joel Technogeeek,
um, I reached out to him because my
neighbor was thinking about buying a
specific, uh, IoT device
>> and was asking me if it was safe.
>> And I was like, uh, they asked me
because they knew that I do hacking and
and AI stuff. And I started looking into
myself. I didn't have a whole lot of
time to look into it. Um, but didn't
find too much on the website of things,
but I saw that the controller was
basically a mobile app. And so I and I
thought this was like a very interesting
company. So I so I messaged Joel and
said, "Hey dude, you should take a look
at this this weekend if you get a
chance. If you're interested, don't
spend too long on it or whatever." And
he was like, "Okay, yeah, sure. I won't,
but yeah, I would love to." And I sent
the same thing to Matt Brown about the
the hardware device. And uh,
>> dude, classic Joel getting nerd sniped
as heck, dude. Oh my gosh. I woke up the
next day. So, this is on a Saturday. I
wake up the next day. Few hours later, I
check my phone and it's like WTF, man.
And there was just a login with Google
button that you click and it sends you
straight to the admin dashboard to see
all the users, all their PII, all the
conversations they've had with the AI.
>> No.
>> And all you had to do, there was no
exploitation necessary. You just click
login with Google.
>> Dude,
>> oh my gosh, dude. So anyway, we're
talking
>> I love that about Joel so much though,
man. Like Joel, it was so awesome, you
know, when I I had him on the pod as
well because, you know, we have these
adventures where I would just send him
like this this link. And then, you know,
he wakes up at like 4 in the morning or
like 3 something in the morning. He's
very early bird. So you wake up and then
he's already like, "Yeah, you know, I
you know, went down this rabbit hole."
And I'm like, "What the heck, dude?"
>> That's funny. Joel is like the
equivalent of my VPS buzzing for me
overnight. You just wake up and Joel has
something interesting for you.
>> Yeah. Throw it to AI. Throw it to Joel.
Throw it to Matt Brown. Yeah,
>> exactly. [laughter]
No. Yeah. Um, it was Yeah, it actually
was a web thing, so I was frustrated
that I didn't find it. Uh, but we've got
some disclosure coming soon, so
everybody will get to see what we're
talking about.
>> Nice, man. Nice. Um, we we are running
close on time. I know we have uh a cut
off today, so let's let's push through
these next.
>> Um, really quick shout out, Defiant
tweeted something nice out here. Um,
when you have a CRLF in the location
header, which is one of the most common
places to do it, if you control the full
location and you can start the location
with a a new line character,
>> you can actually, um, get XSS even on a
302.
>> Um, which is something that I had not
realized.
>> I never knew that.
>> Um,
>> yeah. So, uh, because normally, you
know, CRF in the location header on a
302 really hard to exploit. Not not a
lot of primitives you can use. But if
you can actually just give it an empty
location header, that will actually
render uh HTML
>> the
>> How many times have people found this
and thought it was unexloitable?
>> Yeah, dude. There's like, you know, a
bunch of comments on here saying uh
Yeah. Ah, dang it. I like hacked this up
big time. That's my bad.
>> Um, so good stuff here. I'm going to
jump right into this next one real
quick.
>> Yeah, sure.
>> Um, so guys, uh, Ysef Samura,
I I guess I just don't like monitor his
blog the way I should. He's he's been on
the pod, one of the most prolific client
side hackers, constantly posing or like
poning meta, right? Like just wrecking
them. Um, and so he released a blog post
of like 300K in XSS's on Meta uh via
this conversion API gateway. And I just
wanted to say like this is excellent
scope. Like they open sourced a
serverside solution that they had to
create when the you know cookie tracking
thing kind of went away on Apple a
little bit. Um, so he starts looking at
this and like clear as day, uh, there's
like this event listener that, uh,
doesn't have any origin check and it
allows you to write in a, uh, you know,
local storage key that is later used to
like load a JS file. Um, which seems
like it should be GG right from the
beginning, but of course um, Meta has a
bunch of like crazy uh, defense and
depth mechanisms with CSP and coupe. Um
so he finds a place where he can bypass
the CSP by finding like a route that has
um additional third parties um that are
in the CSP and he also finds a way to
bypass coupe by um
oh okay so cross he bypasses coupe by um
doing this weird trick on Facebook's
Android web view [laughter] where you do
window.name name equals test and
window.open into test and somehow that
allows you to have yourself as the
opener. Um, which is weird. Um, but the
crazy thing that I realized when you
look at this attack flow summary is that
you know he uses a hijacked third party
iframe but like he doesn't have a frame
reference so he can't do that client
side. So he what actually happened here
for this exploit almost certainly is he
actually got rce on the third party
[laughter]
>> and uh and used the like took over the
whole third party like web server
[laughter]
>> hijacked the iframe right I I I don't
know for sure it could have been a
subdomain takeover I find that very
unlikely um
>> but he didn't have a frame reference so
he couldn't pollute the XSS uh you know
or the iframe from the client side he
had to do that from the server
Um, so
>> it just says it just says we exploited a
vulnerability in one of these third
party components to completely hijack
the iframe and later send the malicious
post message from there.
>> The only the only other alternative I
could think of. No, no, it couldn't be
like cookie based stuff because he also
hosts a JS file [laughter and gasps]
>> on on the third party. So he had to
shell this this third party which is
crazy. Um, so very interesting uh attack
flow here. Um, definitely worth reading.
Uh the TLDDR of the situation is you
know he find finds in an XSS uh via the
post message very clean post message
exploit. He bypasses CSP by finding a
relaxed uh you know CSP page that also
has the script on it. He pones a third
party hijacks an iframe to bypass coupe
manipulates a a Facebook Android web
view component to make sure that the
window.opener exists which is something
that was required for this exploit.
sends the the post message from the
hijacked iframe that he got by rce that
loads a JS file from the the third party
that he owned by rce and has now hosting
a JS file there and then that JS file
loads on meta's domain in pops xss.
>> Wow, dude. I wish I could just like open
his brain like a toolbox and just grab
all the little tools like all the little
gadgets like all the little pieces of
information about like how to bypass CSP
on meta, how to bypass coupe on meta,
how to like do this on meta, you know
what I mean? All those little things.
>> Totally. Yeah. And this was a 65k bug, I
I believe. And um yeah, I mean the
persistence needed to find that piece
about the Android web view like
>> that's but how long has it been in his
pocket? That's what I don't know. Right.
>> Well, yeah, he could it could have been
in his pocket or he could have gone and
and pushed pushed pushed pushed pushed
pushed pushed until he found a way to
have an opener on a coupe page. Like
>> Right.
>> Is that kind of a zero day? Like is that
kind of like a thing that most like you
know people don't know about like some
sort of like new gadget? What is there a
word for that? You we need to come up
with a word for that Justin. Like if
there's like a new way like the new way
to or that thing that was found in 2020
by that Google engineer where they could
like set it to null. Like it's basically
like a zero day gadget. It's like here's
a gadget people didn't know about before
that now unlocks a style of attacks that
we didn't know could happen.
>> That's a good that's a good good point.
Zero day gadget. Yeah.
>> There's no like word for that. Yeah.
>> No. No. I don't think so. It's it's
really that those are very valuable and
that's kind of what we're trying to get
right on the research lab for CTB.
Right. Exactly. Uh so, you know, if you
go to lab.ctb.show, we're really trying
to to encourage people to submit micro
research there with little zeroday
gadgets, right? Like,
>> uh this is the way you can do this, this
is the way you can do that, right? Um
and create a sort of a a repository of
that. Um which should be great. Okay,
second bug. Um this bug is kind of nuts,
man. Uh essentially what it looks like
is happening here and and we I have
unfortunately I have to be kind of brief
on this one but this this page that uh
this conversion API gateway that Google
or that Facebook had to stand up because
of the pixel changes
>> um allows you to pipe events through you
know the server side rather than through
the client side because of the pixel
problems. Um, and essentially what it
looks like he found is a is a a place
where you can do dynamically generated
JS uh you know and he he grabbed the the
actual source code for this gateway from
uh Amazon ECR decompiled the jar and
found a place where they are like
creating a JSON object by string
concatenation.
So then he submits a there's an IDOR in
the gateway it seems where you can
configure a rule for any pixel and it
takes one of the the fields from that
idor and um
puts that directly into the rule
generation uh which is done via string
concatenation for for JSON uh inside of
dynamic JavaScript and then it you know
allows him to essentially just poison uh
any pixels
JS file.
>> That's insane.
>> Uh and just run arbitrary code on
everything.
>> Wow.
>> You know
>> how much of that?
>> That one was 250K.
>> Yeah, that's sick.
>> Yeah.
>> It's also just a sick bug.
>> Yeah, super sick. Um so, shout out to
Yousef. Um yeah, these these are
excellent writeups. Anybody who Yeah, I
mean anybody really should go read
Yousef's blog until you understand it.
You know, that is mandatory reading.
Yeah, I love that, dude.
>> All right, man. What you got?
>> I know we've got like a couple minutes.
>> I'm sorry. I'm sorry. One last thing.
Um, quote from the end of this article.
Both vulnerabilities described here stem
from the same root problem. Treating
analytics infrastructure as lowrisisk
code. When JavaScript is shared across
projects, domains, and customers, it
becomes a part of the platform's trusted
computing base. At that point, origin
val validation, strict CSP design, and
safe code generation are no longer
optional. They are existential
requirements. Um,
what what percent of your bugs over the
last year, let's say let's say client
side bugs were either used or broken or
uh manipulated in some way third-party
plugins or third party code or analytics
code
>> very often. You mention it all the time,
>> right? Yeah, you mention that a lot.
>> It is quite a bit.
>> Yeah. So,
>> all right. Sweet. We got like a minute
or two before you got to dip. I know.
Um, one thing really cool, Trail of
Bits. Um, we can put the the link in the
show notes. It's just an expost, but
Trail of Bits released a Claude Skills
um, announcement. And one thing that's
kind of crazy is Claude just released
something yesterday where uh, basically
there's like infinite MCP access.
Basically, it will never pollute more
than 10% of your context with like tools
and MCP. And so if you have like a ton
of them, it will do some sort of like
rag on the tools and skills it has
access to and MCP that it has access to
and only pull in the ones that are
relevant to your query. So now you can
you can fill it chalk full with as many
as you want. I don't have this issue,
but you know, some people out there are
probably installing MCPS like their, you
know, candy or something and they just
have like a thousand of them and then
it's polluting their context. So they're
not limiting that to 10% of the context.
But yeah, if you don't know, Trail of
Bits basically does security research
and there's a bunch of really cool
skills in here. I have not dug into all
of them. Um, but anyways, I got a bunch
of them like audit, context building,
burpuite, project parser, sim grip, rule
creator, constant time analysis, um, you
know, reverse engineering development,
team management. There's like a ton of
really cool skills from a company that
does really great research and they
released it in the last day. So, really
cool. [snorts]
>> Yeah, dude, that's awesome. We'll we'll
drop that link in the description.
>> Um, hey, uh, I I I just got a message.
I'm good.
>> You're good to keep going for a few
minutes?
>> Yeah, I am. Oh, sweet.
>> Yeah.
>> Cool. I'll go ahead and roll into
another one since you've got two more.
Oh, you might have three more. You've
got a lot on your list.
>> I do have a lot. I'm sorry. I I I got
excited. There a lot of good writeups,
but yeah, dude. Go ahead. You take your
next one. I'll go after that.
>> Oh, you're fine. Yeah. Um actually, I
don't have too many. Yeah. The So, um
Zink, the adorminator um
>> posted something. Let me I'll share my
screen on this one.
Screen. This one.
>> Ah, dude. Yeah, this was a great a great
tweet.
>> So, this is really really interesting.
Um, obviously this is a $55,000 bug and
you know, actuators are still
everywhere, which is absurd, but they
really are, especially when you're
getting into like deep and legacy paths
on like old on um you know, legacy
targets like I'm just going to throw out
names like Yahoo or whatever like
companies like that that have had a
bunch of old architecture, a bunch of
old stuff.
>> Um, when you're fuzzing for them, you
know, clearly they don't always show up.
Sometimes you see like 403s or 401's or
whatever, but I just thought an encoded
um like hashtag symbol was like such a
weird thing to work here. I I had I
hadn't seen that before. Um and it makes
me want to go refuzz like every company
ever that has legacy paths like this
because you know I I what I'm what I'm
considering doing is creating a list.
What's kind of cool is Jason shared this
thing hack tips. Hopefully it'll switch
straight to this. Basically, this hack
tips repo is just it's kind of underpop
populated, but Jason Haddock um you know
released a list of actuator endpoints
and everybody knows these these actuator
endpoints, but um there's also a 403
bypass here.
>> Um and then you know these are built
into 403 bypasser, you know, plugins on
on both burp and Kaido, but just go grab
all of those and then kind of like pre
um pre-apply them in every variation to
all these actuator endpoints. Now, of
course, you're not going to get hits if
you're just fuzzing this at the root.
But I want to have all those such that
when I do fuzz deep in an API path,
those are like automatically on my word
list, right? Like a bunch of variations,
like basically every possible variation
of these actuator endpoints with all the
403 bypasses already appended. Um,
>> and that does kind of well, one, I mean,
if people aren't looking at uh Zwink's
writeups, I think you definitely should
because they're like very simple, highly
effective vulnerabilities. But I um but
that did yeah make me want to fix that
about my current fuzzing and um it was
like a perfect time to kind of remention
the FFUF master class. So I've been
prepping for it and I like I have
leveled up. I need to show it to you. Um
all of the like a bunch of different
stuff that I'm doing with FFUF and it's
um pretty sweet. So yeah, I'm excited
about that.
>> Nice man. Yeah, that that'll be good. I
think that you know adding So just for
the audio listeners, I'm not sure if we
read the whole thing. the the the
path here was SL actuator/heap dump
percent 23, right? Um
>> but and it and it was at a that was
after some other path. It wasn't just at
the root
>> and it could be just after random path.
My thought is probably it's after a path
and then a path traversal
>> is is my thought. Um so definitely hit
those actuator endpoints on all of these
various paths. also append path
traversals before that you know um you
know with with backslashes with
semicolons um and you might be able to
find some of these uh actuator endpoints
I I I think it's also really important
to highlight here that combining
multiple techniques here is probably
going to get you the best result right
>> path you know doing it as a subpath
adding a path traversal
>> authenticating
>> and then adding and then adding a uh uh
you know um character encoding or
something like that. Yep.
>> Did you said and authenticated? Yeah.
Like so. So So if you're at a deep path
where people aren't normally looking and
you're authenticated and you know
because there's usually wonky routing at
a lot of these API paths where it's
actually vhosting under the hood or
whatever like you said like Justin just
said sometimes you want to patch averse
back up to the root because it's on some
other server that's running the spring
boot actuator but you know you're you're
not at the root so you actually don't
have access to those endpoints. So now
you're like, yeah, basically you need to
be authenticated deep into some of these
paths and then also find something that
actually bypasses the the um
>> the WF rule or whatever blocking you.
Yeah.
>> Yeah, absolutely, man. Good good shout
there. All right, I'm going to cover one
by um by Flat Security. Um these guys
are freaking great. Uh I've got a couple
buddies that work for them. Uh Yotak
obviously is is the guy that that's
writing this one. Um,
>> you were just talking about how the they
seem to like gobble up so many great
researchers over there.
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. I mean, if you're in
Japan, they're gonna they're going to
try to slurp you up. Um, yeah. Uh, but
this research was phenomenal and very
much Sasugyotak. It's very much like
him, you know, to to do this research.
Um the scdr of the situation was in
cloud code there are allow lists right
which um will you're able to run
commands uh without getting permission
from the user uh for a certain set of
commands like echo you know sort said
that sort of thing right and so you know
just comes in here and just destroys it
right so he found eight different
bypasses and I'm going to try to grab
the highle techniques from each one of
them um and apply them. So first one
here this is awesome scope right you
know understanding where the threat
model is for co or for cloud code and
realizing okay can I bypass this
permission check here really good scope
he looks into how it's implemented and
it's reax okay so whenever you're using
reax to parse a command you should pay
extra attention there um because there's
so many gotchas and you can't just say
stuff like yeah they can use the man
command that's fine right because um
you've got stuff like this uh man--HTML
equals touch tempon.
>> That totally makes sense. That totally
makes sense that you can pass bash into
the d--HTML tag to execute RC, right?
Makes sense to me.
>> I I you know, I just looked at this for
a second. I was like, why does the HTML,
you know, but but it says is there's
another dangerous option called-hows
users to specify command to render the
manual pages as HTML.
>> Right.
>> So, it's allowing you to define the
renderer.
>> Yeah,
>> of course. Yeah. Um then he does it
again with sort. Um because sort allows
you to define a compression program. Um
he does it with history. Um uh like
using the - a um and - s options um and
just completely bypasses all of those.
Um, moving down to the next one, he also
does uh a bypass using git because cloud
code allows you to do some git commands
uh but it filters out malicious
arguments. Um,
>> and one of them is unload pack uh in um
git ls remote. The cool thing about this
is that git actually parses abbreviated
arguments. I didn't know this. Um, but
you can use, you know, d-upload-pa
>> and because there's nothing else besides
pack that you could mean, there's some
autocomplete code in the git source code
that will actually convert that to-pack.
>> Can I just say I'm so glad we don't work
on the defensive side of things.
>> I know, dude.
>> That feels so frustrating. Like, how can
you even predict that, you know? It's
like, oh, this random thing is Yeah.
>> It's much more fun being on this side
where we're like, we can nitpick, you
know, versus like you have to be
perfect, you know?
>> Right. It is.
>> Yeah. So, anyway, he was able to bypass
this. Um, I think this is a really
applicable technique. Um, so if you guys
are hacking on anything with git related
to git, which a lot of things are built
on top of git, and you have the ability
to specify an argument, you might be
able to use this autocomp completion um,
uh, technique here
>> to get around some sort of like
blacklist. Yeah,
>> exactly. Exactly. Um, he does it with
said, uh, apparently dash slash e at the
end of said will just let you run
commands. Uh, which I didn't know. Um
and then he this is another one that I
wanted to shout uh which is a very um a
very cool technique. Xorgs is one of the
whitelisted um commands. Uh but there's
a a very limited amount of things you
can do with it. Uh echo printf WC Grep
head and tail. Um the problem is it it
does allow you to specify flags. Uh but
it assumes that those flags will consume
the next argument which it doesn't
always do. So in this scenario, XRS-T
touch echo, right? It is assuming that
touch is the
>> um going to get slurped up by -ash t.
>> Yep.
>> Right. But -ash t is just a a boolean
flag,
>> right?
>> Um so touch is actually the next item,
you know, in x which allows you to just
run any command. Um so that like that um
different interpretation of command
arguments allowed him to bypass with
exorgs and then also with rip greb.
>> Um
absolute pwnage man.
>> Yes.
>> Frick. Um okay. This is also I have no
idea if Riot used it. This is also one
of those like really good use cases for
LLM to come up with lots of like to
generate ideas for how you could bypass
these, you know.
>> Totally. Yeah. All right. Number eight.
We're gonna link this article in the
description. I don't know that I can
explain this. Uh [snorts] but I've never
seen this before in my life. Uh so go
check it out if you don't understand
what I'm saying. Um he bypasses this one
using bash variable expansion. Um and
apparently cuz I I've heard of bash
variable expansion, right? You do the
dollar sign, the curly brackets, and
then you put something in there. Y
>> um apparently there's also a atp
modifier that you can add into this
which will um let me read it. This is
possible because variable expansion
supports the atp modifier which parses
the value of the variable as a prompt
string in bash. Prompt strings support
special uh escape sequences including
command substitution. So he's able to
essentially convert a string into
command substitution string which allows
you to run arbitrary commands. Um
>> so
>> what the freick.
>> Yeah. So there so there's variable
expansion with an atp modifier that has
a command substitution payload in it.
>> So when [clears throat] appp is applied
to the variable, bash interprets it as
if it were a prompt string which then
does the command substitution which then
allows it to execute.
>> Yeah.
What the freak? you know.
[clears throat]
>> Um, so crazy stuff here.
>> And then and then he also sets the
variable to the dollar sign.
>> Yeah. Yeah. You see that right there?
You know, so and then he he can appends
that dollar sign in front of the, you
know, dollar sign parenthesis,
>> right?
>> Right. Crazy crazy stuff. So, um, this
is definitely a good read. These are the
kind of things that will get you rce. A
lot of times people ask like, "How do
you get RC? What's your technique for
getting rce? Like understanding quirks
of stuff like this and then finding
functionality where they're doing
something funky like passing it to a
command line um you know a shell or
something like that.
>> This is the kind of stuff that gets to
RC.
>> Yeah. Actually, I think this would be
really interesting if you did have a
place where something was going to
command line to apply a bunch of these
techniques because I bet it would bypass
protections that people in the past have
been stumped by.
>> I'm sure.
>> You know what I mean?
>> Yeah.
>> All right. You're up next. What you got?
Um,
I think that's everything. Um,
>> is that it? Okay. You want me to do this
last one?
>> Yeah. Do your last thing and then I've
got one closing comment.
>> Okay. All right. Last one is a write up
by Watchtower Labs. Um, they've been
putting out some good stuff, guys. We've
covered them on the pod many times. Um,
so definitely uh something to keep an
eye on. This one is entitled, "Do smart
people ever say they're smart?" Which is
a pre-auth
tools, smarter mail. Oh my goodness.
>> Yeah. Which is uh I just love reading
their writeups, too, because they're so
punchy. You know, you read it and
they're like, "Oh, well, you know, are
they that smart?"
>> Um and they they have this meme. Let me
scroll down here. Where's the Yeah,
they've got the like, you know,
history.com meme with the aliens guy.
Yes. And then uh [laughter]
>> Yeah. And then they've got um where's
the other one? Oh, down here. The the
office meme, you know, where the manager
is shaking his hand. Um, so very fun.
The write up is a pre-author RC in
Smarter Mail. Um, and it's it's pretty
vanilla, guys. You know, like
essentially they they signal it by
looking at the patch and oh, there's a
GID validation that's added to the patch
that pretty much tells you exactly where
the vulnerability is, right? Um, so they
start looking into how this GID is used.
It's in the API upload route, right? Um,
and there's a a um multi-art form data
where you can upload an attachment to
Smarter Mail um from an unauthenticated
context. The GID is then embedded into
the file name um which you can see right
here and then you can use that to do
path traversal um and traverse all the
way back up and write a web shell. Um
and so the final exploit is pretty
simple. You've got the um uh you know
GID definition here with a bunch of um
patch reversals. You've got the
resumable file name that provides the
file extension. Um and then you you
write your web shell uh inside of that
um form data or multipart form data
upload uh and that gets written to the
the web route. Um
>> pretty awesome find, pretty simple.
Seriously,
>> we should we should probably be
reversing patches more often and and
using AI to do that extremely
efficiently.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I think that I've seen lots
of research around how how good it is at
that. Um and we've talked a little bit
about Caleb Grass's research on um on
rank for doing that specifically. So
then going and finding the code blocks
that are changed that you know apply
that fix. So
>> yeah, we definitely should.
>> My one quick thing was um
>> whenever we talked about I'm sorry, one
more thing on this. I just realized this
is what I was talking about with the
punchy things at the end. It says um at
the end it says, "As an aside, it seems
that Smarter Mail uh scans all
attachments with Clam AV as shown in the
below screenshot. However, either Clam
AV is unable to recognize a basic web
shell uh or Smarter Mail is unable to
process Clam AV results."
>> That's funny. Yeah, that is funny. So,
uh, yeah, I just thought it was fun that
they scan it and then they either don't
do anything with results or clam AV
can't detect like a super basic web
shell.
>> Exactly. There's either there's some bug
there, which obviously you can obuscate,
but the fact that it couldn't even
detect the plain one is sad.
>> That's sad.
>> No. Yeah. I was going to mention that um
>> I asked my wife, I was like, you know,
what do you think is my favorite worship
song? And she mentioned um that you
know, for a long time and I think it
probably still is. It was like King of
My Heart. So,
>> for people who are waiting on that,
>> yeah, we talked about that. Was it two
weeks ago when this will air? Probably.
Yeah, two weeks ago.
>> And I got some comments saying that they
uh that people on XED has for those of
people who had not heard of Forest
Frank, they've been jamming to it. So, I
love that.
>> Forest Force Frank is like catchy as
heck, dude. It's crazy.
>> Um All right, man. I think that's a
wrap. Yeah.
>> Yep. Sounds good, guys. Thanks.
>> All right. Peace, y'all. [music] That's
the spot.
>> And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, [music]
uh or if you want to support the show,
head over to ctvb.show. show/isord. You
can hop in the community. There's lots
of great highlevel [music] hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild
if you're a full-time hunter. [music]
It's a great time. Trust me. All right,
I'll see you there.